Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kavishankar (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Azure Databricks
Azure Data Factory
Event-driven

Certifications
JUnit

Kavishankar Karunakaran

AWS Solution Architect (SAA) | Full Stack Java Developer | MuleSoft Integration Developer | Senior API Developer at Commonwealth Equity Services

Greater Boston

Summary

AWS Solution Architect | Full Stack Java Developer | Kafka and Cassandra developer

Highly innovative and an effective Big data and Java Full-Stack developer with 14 years of experience. Have designed and Implemented

modern Data platform for Bloomberg Reference data & Full stack application with SpringBoot Microservice, No-SQL

Cassandra Database, Kafka data streaming framework, Axon Event driven

framework, Multi-Cloud & Docker based Cloud agnostic solutions.

Completed Master of Business Administration (MBA) and Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) in Computer Science from Anna University

Experience

Commonwealth Financial Network
Senior API Developer (Senior Full Stack Engineer at Data Integrations)
December 2021 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Waltham, Massachusetts, United States

Cognizant

7 years 5 months

Architect Projects

November 2021 - December 2021 (2 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Consultant @ BNYMellon

Asset Management and Wealth Management product development

Central Security Master system development. BackOffice security data sourcing from Bloomberg, Refinitiv, ICE, CRD State Street and many other vendors.

Sr Associate Projects

July 2018 - October 2021 (3 years 4 months)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Consultant @ BNYMellon

Asset Management and Wealth Management product development

Associate Projects

August 2014 - July 2018 (4 years)

Chennai Area, India

Consultant @ BNYMellon | Eagle Investment System

Asset Management and Wealth Management product development

Consultant @ PepsiCo

Product Gallery Portal Development

Aon Hewitt

3 years 1 month

IND Software Engineer II

October 2013 - August 2014 (11 months)

myHR product implementation

PeopleSoft, SAP and WorkDay integration for client(s): PepsiCo, McGraw Hill,

Chubb

IND Software Engineer I

August 2011 - October 2013 (2 years 3 months)

First Internet Systems

Software Engineer

August 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 1 month)

SOM (Service Operations Manager)

ESB (Enterprise Service Bus)

product development

Mir3 and many other SMPP provider integrations

Education

Anna University

Master of Business Administration (MBA), General Studies · (2011 - 2013)

Anna University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science · (2006 - 2010)